privacyrevolution.org 2008-12-20

# ALA | Privacy Statement

American Library Association

Privacy Statement

Thank you for visiting the American Library Association website and reviewing our privacy statement.  The American Library Association is committed to protecting the privacy of our members, donors, customers, and other contacts. Our privacy policy is clear:  We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us.   

Any information you choose to provide on the website will only be used to provide or improve services. ALA guards your privacy and appreciates your trust.   

You may inform us of your communication preferences at any time by visiting our online Communications Preferences page.

Personally identifying information that you provide by e-mails or web forms will be used only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection (for example on a web form), such as to send information or products to you, update your membership record, or to respond to your questions or comments. If you provide contact information, ALA staff or its contractors may contact you to clarify your comment or question, or to learn about your level of customer satisfaction with our services.   

Any credit card information you provide for goods or services is secure and used only for your intended purpose.

During your visit as you browse through the web site, read pages, or download information, we will automatically gather and store certain information about your visit but not about you. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about the visit:  

  1. The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if a private Internet access account, or "aschool.edu" if connected from a university) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it is surfing the Web) from which access to our web site is gained;
  2. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;   
  3. The date and time of access to our site;   
  4. The pages visited and for how long; and 
  5. The address of the website from which the initial visit to [www.ala.org](http://www.ala.org/) was launched, if any.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors and to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use.  The data that are collected are not connected to your personal information or identity.

This Website contains links to other sites. The American Library Association is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites, which may be different from the privacy practices described in this policy. . We encourage you to become familiar with privacy practices of other sites you visit, including linked sites.

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, the American Library Association uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. 

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and 18 U.S.C. Sec. 1001 and 1030.  Information also may be used for authorized law enforcement investigations. Except for the above purposes, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits.

We reserve the right to change or modify this privacy statement at any time.  If we revise our privacy statement, we will post those changes on the homepage and other places so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

1 The term "members and customers" as used in this statement includes ALA members, customers, donors, or any individual or organization having contact or conducting transactions with the Association. Also see the American Library Association's Web page on [privacy resources](http://www.ala.org/ala/deletedcontent.cfm?am_cms=%2ftemplate%2ecfm%3fsection%3difissues%26amp%3btemplate%3d%2fcontentmanagement%2fcontentdisplay%2ecfm%26amp%3bcontentid%3d2427&pub_loc=http%3a%2f%2fwww%2eala%2eorg%2fcontent%2fnavigationmenu%2four%5fassociation%2foffices%2fintellectual%5ffreedom3%2fintellectual%5ffreedom%5fissues%2fdefault883%2ehtm).
